Guide to the Lynn Riggs Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1924-54; Series II; 7.25; (17 boxes)
  - WRITINGS OF OTHERS
    - O'Neil, George
      - "Concerning Judgements," typescript (with note), n.d. (Box 24, Folder 413)
      - "Crusade -- 1929," typescript, n.d.
      - "Delayed Music," typescript carbon, signed, n.d.
      - "Description," typescript, n.d.
      - "Enough of the Sea," typescript, 1928 Nov 28
      - "For Instinct," typescript carbon (with note), 1929 Jan 4 (Box 24, Folder 414)
      - "For Theseus or Any Man,: typescript, n.d.
      - "For the World's Weather," typescript (with note), n.d.
      - "Fury at Conversation," typescript carbon, signed, n.d.
      - "The Hunter," typescript, n.d.
      - "Insufficient Magic" [article], printed version, The Outlook, 1927 Nov 23
      - "An Opinion in Metaphor," typescript, n.d.
      - "An Opinion in Metaphor," printed version, 1928 Dec 26
      - "Poems" (Scrapbook of printed poems kept by Lynn Riggs), n.d. (Box 24, Folder 415)
      - "Prescription and Reproof," typescript carbon, corrected (Box 24, Folder 416)
      - "Recorded for a Tormented Man," typescript, n.d.
      - "Reminder," typescript, 1928 Oct 27
      - "Socrates Prays," typescript carbon, 1927 Jul 6
      - "Speech to Some Future Generation," typescript, corrected, n.d.
      - "This Day," typescript, corrected and carbon (with note), 1928 Dec 15 (Box 24, Folder 417)
      - "This Man's Prejudice," typescript and carbon, 1927 Oct
      - "To People Who Forget Their Eyes," typescript, n.d.
      - "Tribute (To the Sentient Being)" typescript, corrected, n.d.
      - "Vengeful Trick," typescript carbon (with note), n.d. (Box 24, Folder 418)
      - "Very Simple Maxims," typescript, n.d.
      - Notes, 1928, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 419)
    - Roosevelt, Elliot
      - The Copper Earth, typescript carbon (with notes), 1933 (Box 24, Folder 420)
    - Sage, Frances
      - "Blitzkreig" drafts, typescript and carbon, corrected, 1942 (Box 24, Folder 421)
    - Stromberg, Hunt
      - "Laughing Boy" synopsis, typescript carbon, 1933 Jun 24 (Box 24, Folder 422)
    - Thompson, Paul
      - "Claremore Mound," and "Osage --- Cherokee," typescript (Box 24, Folder 423)
    - Wilson, Edmund
      - "Never Apologize, Never Explain: The Art of Evelyn Waugh," typescript carbon, 1944 Mar 4 (Box 24, Folder 424)
    - Unidentified
      - Poems, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 425)
      - Suggestions for Lynn Riggs, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 426)
- Personal Papers, 1929-54; Series III; 1; (3 boxes)
  Series III, Personal Papers, is arranged alphabetically by type of item.
  - Address book, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 427)
  - Bibliography of Lynn Riggs' library, 1936-41 (Box 25, Folder 428)
  - Bibliography of Lynn Riggs' library by genre, 1954 (Box 25, Folder 429)
  - Business card - Lucy Kroll Agency, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 430)
  - Calendar, 1942 (Box 25, Folder 431)
  - Calendar, 1943 (Box 25, Folder 432)
  - Calendar, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 433)
  - Calendar, 1945 (Box 25, Folder 434)
  - Calendar, 1946 (Box 26, Folder 435)
  - Calendar, 1947 (Box 26, Folder 436)
  - Calendar, 1948 (Box 26, Folder 437)
  - Calendar, 1949 (Box 26, Folder 438)
  - Calendar, 1952 (Box 26, Folder 439)
  - Certificate, National Geographic Society, 1934 Dec 11 (Box 26, Folder 440)
  - Certificate of vaccination for dog, 1936 Aug 14 (Box 26, Folder 441)
  - Charcoal sketch by unidentified artist, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 442)
  - Cherokee Indian rolls note (Box 26, Folder 443)
  - Christmas list, 1933 (Box 26, Folder 444)
  - Constitution, Writers' Editions, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 445)
  - Copyright registration application for a Dramatic or Dramatico-musical composition [blank], n.d. (Box 26, Folder 446)
  - Diet menu, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 447)
  - Documents concerning immigration visa for Enrique Gasque-Molina (Ramon Naya), 1937 Dec (Box 26, Folder 448)
  - Home Renovation - Santa Fe
    - Bills and receipts, 1934-36 (Box 26, Folder 449)
    - Inventories, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 450)
    - Notes, 1934 (Box 26, Folder 451)
    - Sketch, 1933-34 (Box 26, Folder 452)
  - Home renovation - Shelter Island
    - Appliance information and paint samples, 1947
      See: Oversize, Box 32, folder 545
    - Drawings [watercolor], 1947
      See: Oversize, Box 32, folder 546
    - Notes, 1947
      See: Oversize, Box 32, folder 547
    - Reconstruction log, 1947 (Box 26, Folder 453)
  - Library cards, 1943, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 454)
  - List of guests, 1933 Dec (Box 26, Folder 455)
  - List of persons receiving copy of Listen, Mind (Box 26, Folder 456)
  - List of persons receiving copy of Roadside, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 457)
  - List of plays by Lynn Riggs, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 458)
  - Mailing list - Toward the Western Sky, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 459)
  - Membership cards, 1930-44 (Box 26, Folder 460)
  - Military documents, 1942-44 (Box 26, Folder 461)
  - Notebook in shorthand (Box 26, Folder 462)
  - Notebook - Spanish vocabulary and conjugations, 1944 Sep-Nov (Box 26, Folder 463)
  - Notes, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 464)
  - Passenger receipt - Europe to New York, 1929 Apr (Box 27, Folder 465)
  - Phonograph record log, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 466)
  - Plan for study made by John Schlick for the John Simon Guggenheim Foundation, ca. 1934 (Box 27, Folder 467)
  - Postcard - Lamy, New Mexico, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 468)
  - Press release about Lynn Riggs by Garrett Leverton from Samuel French, Inc., 1946 Oct 14 (Box 27, Folder 469)
  - Press releases - The Dramatists Guild, 1936 Oct (Box 27, Folder 470)
  - Radio interview with Lynn Riggs, script, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 471)
  - Recipes (in Spanish), n.d. (Box 27, Folder 472)
  - Scrapbook, 1940-41
    See: Oversize, Box 32, folder 548
  - Sign - "No Trespassing", 1934 Nov 23 (Box 27, Folder 473)
  - Stationery - Lynn Riggs, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 474)
  - Sympathy acknowledgement sent out after the death of Lynn Riggs, 1954 (Box 27, Folder 475)
- Financial and Legal Papers, 1924-51; Series IV; 0.5; (1 box)
  Series IV, Financial and Legal Papers, is arranged alphabetically by type of material.
  - Automobile insurance and registration, 1943-51 (Box 28, Folder 476)
  - Bank account statements, 1941-43 (Box 28, Folder 477)
  - Bills and receipts, 1922-45 (Box 28, Folder 478-479)
  - Box office statement for Domino Parlor, 1928 Jun (Box 28, Folder 480)
  - Checkbook stubs, 1944 (Box 28, Folder 481)
  - Contracts
    - Agents, 1933-39 (Box 28, Folder 482)
    - Works, 1928-45 (Box 28, Folder 483)
  - Foreclosure papers, 1924-25 (Box 28, Folder 484)
  - Household budgets, 1934 Feb-Apr (Box 28, Folder 485)
  - Income tax returns, 1930-36
    See: Oversize, Box 32, folder 549
  - Leases, 1933-34 (Box 28, Folder 486)
  - Ledger (kept by Lynn Riggs while in Paris), ca. 1928-29 (Box 28, Folder 487)
  - Preproduction expenses tally sheet for All the Way Home, 1948 (Box 28, Folder 488)
  - Royalty statements
    - For The Iron Dish, 1931 (Box 28, Folder 489)
    - Samuel French, Inc., 1927-34, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 490)
- Photographs, 1928-54; Series V; 0.5; (1 box)
  Series V, Photographs, is arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - All the Way Home dress rehearsal, 1948 (Box 29, Folder 491-492)
  - Horgan, Paul, 1936 (Box 29, Folder 493)
  - "House, Gui, Lynn in Taos" series [12 negatives, 10 prints], 1947 Feb (Box 29, Folder 494)
  - Laughler[?], Walter, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 495)
  - Laughter from a Cloud production, ca. 1948 (Box 29, Folder 496)
  - Long, Haniel, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 497)
  - O'Neil, George, ca. 1930-40 (Box 29, Folder 498)
  - Riggs, Lynn
    - with Joan Crawford, Jerry Asher and Franchot Tone, ca. 1935 (Box 29, Folder 499)
    - with Group of party-goers (Cannes-sur-Mer, France), ca. 1928 (Box 29, Folder 500)
    - Informal portrait series, ca. 1951 (Box 29, Folder 501-502)
    - Military photographs, ca. 1942 (Box 29, Folder 503)
    - Portraits, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 504)
    - with George Gershwin, ca. 1940 (Box 29, Folder 505)
    - with Unidentified woman, ca. 1952 (Box 29, Folder 506)
    - Santa Fe house with visitors [negatives], ca. 1934 (Box 29, Folder 507)
    - Scenes from unidentified play, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 508)
      See also: Oversize, Box 32, folder 550
    - Shelter Island[?] series, ca. 1948 (Box 29, Folder 509)
    - Shelter Island[?] series, ca. 1954 Apr (Box 29, Folder 510)
    - Unidentified persons, 1932, 1943, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 511)
- Printed Material, 1924-53; Series VI; 0.75; (2 boxes)
  Series VI, Printed Material, is arranged alphabetically by type of material.
  - Book jacket - Oklahoma!, [1943] (Box 30, Folder 512)
  - Clippings
    - Friends and acquaintances, 1929-53 (Box 30, Folder 513)
    - Human interest stories, 1924-53 (Box 30, Folder 514)
    - Limón, José, 1948 (Box 30, Folder 515)
    - Naya, Ramon, 1941-45
    - News features, 1930-53, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 516)
    - Oklahoma!, 1946-53 (Box 30, Folder 517)
    - Poems, 1926
    - Riggs, Lynn - Profiles and notices, 1934-52, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 518)
    - Riggs, Lynn - Works, 1942-53 (Box 30, Folder 519)
    - Santa Fe, 1939 (Box 30, Folder 520)
    - Theatre, 1927, 1948
  - Hollywood Reporter, 1934 Feb 15 (Box 30, Folder 521)
  - Invitation broadside for Oklahoma! 1st Anniversary party, 1944
    See: Oversize, Box 32, folder 550
  - Maps, 1943, 1952, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 522)
  - Menus, [1928], n.d.
  - Operating instructions for radio-phonograph [with parts], ca. 1950 (Box 30, Folder 523)
  - Pamphlets, ca. 1930-50 (Box 30, Folder 524)
  - El Pasatiempo [Supplement to the Santa Fe New Mexican ], 1931 Sep 5 (Box 30, Folder 525)
  - Posters [with tickets], [1928] (Box 30, Folder 526)
  - Programs
    - Four Saints in Three Acts, 1934 (Box 30, Folder 527)
    - Lectures by Lynn Riggs, 1952 (Box 30, Folder 528)
    - The Lost Colony by Paul Green, 1940, 1951 (Box 30, Folder 529)
    - Mourning Becomes Electra [film], 1947 (Box 30, Folder 530)
    - Performances by José Limón, 1952 (Box 30, Folder 531)
    - The Philadelphia Story [play] featuring Gui Machado, 1947 Feb (Box 30, Folder 532)
    - Plays advisory directed by Lynn Riggs, 1941 (Box 30, Folder 533)
    - Plays by Lynn Riggs, 1932-51 (Box 30, Folder 534-536)
    - Miscellaneous, 1928-52 (Box 31, Folder 537)
  - The Prompter's Cue Sheet [newsletter] Baylor University, 1945 Jan 9 (Box 31, Folder 538)
  - Sheet Music
    - "I Left My Heart at the Stage Door Canteen" by Irving Berlin, 1942 (Box 31, Folder 539)
    - "This is the Army, Mister Jones" by Irving Berlin, 1942 (Box 31, Folder 540)
  - Telephone directories
    - Claremore, Oklahoma, 1927 (Box 31, Folder 541)
    - Santa Fe, New Mexico, 1931
  - Miscellaneous printed items, 1930-50 (Box 31, Folder 542)
- Oversize, 1927-47; 1.75; (1 box)
  Oversize, contains material from Series II, III, IV, V, and VI, arranged in series order.
  - Writings
    - Plays
      - Borned in Texas [Roadside]
        - Production blueprints for Festival Theatre Production, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 543)
    - Writings of Others
      - Meyer, Karl
        - "Sunrise" [screenplay], typescript carbon, bound, 1927 (Box 32, Folder 544)
  - Personal Papers
    - Home Renovations - Shelter Island
      - Appliance information and paint samples, 1947 (Box 32, Folder 545)
      - Drawings [watercolor], 1947 (Box 32, Folder 546)
      - Notes, 1947 (Box 32, Folder 547)
    - Scrapbook
      - Scrapbook, 1940-41 (Box 32, Folder 548)
  - Financial and Legal Papers
    - Income tax returns, 1930-36 (Box 32, Folder 549)
  - Photographs
    - Scene from unidentified play, ca. 1930 (Box 32, Folder 550)
  - Printed Material
    - Invitation broadside for Oklahoma! 1st Anniversary party (Box 32, Folder 550)